this is the Mars rover perseverance
这就是火星漫游者的毅力
the most advanced robot to land on another planet
登陆另一个星球的最先进的机器人
in this video we'll take a look at how it was built
在这个视频中，我们将看看它是如何建造的
the Atlas 5 launch
Atlas 5发布
the journey to Mars
火星之旅
and the scientific instruments
和科学仪器
that allow it to study the surface
让它能够研究表面
on February 2021
2021年2月
a perseverance rover successfully touched down on Mars
一辆坚持不懈的漫游者成功登陆火星
it costs a total of 25 billion US dollars
总共要花250亿美元
it has many scientific instruments to help study Mars
它有许多科学仪器来帮助研究火星
search for signs of life
寻找生命迹象
and prepare the way for future human explorers
并为未来的人类探险家铺平道路
perseverance is of course
毅力当然是
not the first rover to visit Mars
不是第一个访问火星的漫游者
sojourner was in 1997 a very small rover
旅居者在1997年是一个非常小的漫游者
and here's a person for size comparison
这是一个比较尺寸的人。
spirit and opportunity in 2004
2004年的精神与机遇
these were identical rovers
这些是一模一样的漫游者
sent just a few weeks apart from each other
彼此相隔几周发送
curiosity landed in 2012
好奇心在2012年登陆
and then perseverance in 2021
然后在2021年坚持不懈
same size as curiosity
和好奇心一样大
but much more advanced technology
但更先进的技术
this is not a complete list
这不是一个完整的列表
this just shows the most recent rovers sent by NASA
这只是美国航天局最近发送的漫游者
in the United States
在美国
for most of this video I'll be focusing on perseverance
在这个视频的大部分时间里，我会把重点放在毅力上。
NASA designs and builds the rovers in Pasadena
美国航天局在帕萨迪纳设计和制造漫游者
California
加利福尼亚州
at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory or JPL for short
喷气推进实验室或简称喷气推进实验室
this took about eight years of designing
这花了大约八年的设计时间
building and testing to get perseverance ready to go
建立和测试，让毅力做好准备
it was built in a clean room
它是在一个干净的房间里建造的
that's free from dust or other contaminants
没有灰尘或其他污染物
it's designed to work on another planet
它被设计成在另一个星球上工作
different atmosphere different gravity
不同的大气不同的重力
and most of all no repair station
最重要的是没有维修站
it has to be engineered
它必须经过设计
so well that it can last for years on its own
如此之好，以至于它可以自己持续数年
on top of that
除此之外
it has to be light and compact
它必须轻巧紧凑
so it can fit inside of the launch vehicle
所以它可以安装在运载火箭内部
once it was ready to go
一旦它准备好了
the rover was carefully packaged up
漫游者被精心包装
and then flown across the United States
然后飞越美国
to Kennedy Space Center
到肯尼迪航天中心
in Florida this is where the launch happened
在佛罗里达州，这是发射发生的地方
the same place that NASA has been launching rockets
就是美国航天局发射火箭的地方
since the 1960s
自20世纪60年代以来
perseverance was installed
毅力被安装
along with several other components
以及其他几个组件
that went along for the journey to Mars
一起去火星旅行
we'll talk about each one of these pieces
我们将讨论这些作品中的每一件
later in the video
稍后在视频中
this was all put inside of the payload fairing
这都是放在有效载荷整流罩内的
then taken to the rocket
然后被带到火箭上
and then lifted up to the very top
然后上升到最高处
this rocket is called an Atlas 5
这枚火箭叫做阿特拉斯5号
it's made by a company called
它是由一家名为
the United Launch Alliance
联合发射联盟
or ULA for short
或简称ULA
let me point out
让我指出
that the rover was actually upside down
火星车实际上是颠倒的
for the launch
为了发射
the best time to launch to Mars is about every
发射到火星的最佳时间大约是每
26 months if we show this with the correct scale
如果我们用正确的比例显示这个，26个月
you can barely even see the sun
你几乎看不到太阳
for this animation
对于这个动画
I'm going to show this
我来展示一下
out of scale so we can see this a little better
规模过大，这样我们可以更好地看到这个。
for the earth to get around the sun
地球绕着太阳转
it takes exactly one year right
正好需要一年，对吧？
no surprises there
那里没有惊喜
Mars on the other hand
另一方面，火星。
takes almost two years to get around the sun
绕着太阳转几乎要两年
the best time to launch is right before
发射的最佳时间就在之前
earth and Mars are lined up this
地球和火星是这样排列的
is called a launch window and it happens about every
被称为启动窗口，它发生在每个
26 months
26个月
perseverance was launched on July 2020
毅力于2020年7月推出
the four solid rocket boosters use up all their fuel
四个固体火箭助推器耗尽了所有燃料
first
第一
at 1 minute 49 seconds
1分49秒
they are jettisoned or separated from the rocket
它们被抛弃或与火箭分离
at 3 minutes 27 seconds
3分27秒
the payload fairing is jettisoned
有效载荷整流罩被丢弃
which exposes the spacecraft
这暴露了飞船
next up the main booster runs out of fuel
接下来主助推器燃料耗尽
at 4 minutes 28 seconds the main booster is separated
4分28秒主助推器分离
and it will fall back to the earth
它会落回地球
this is called the Centaur stage
这叫半人马座阶段
its main engine now fires up
它的主引擎现在启动了
this is what gets us into orbit around the earth
这就是让我们进入绕地球轨道的原因
at 11 minutes and 30 seconds the engines shut off
11分30秒时引擎熄火
this is called the coast phase
这就是所谓的海岸阶段
we'll stay here for about a half hour
我们会在这里呆半个小时
it's a good time to check things out
这是检查东西的好时机
and make sure that everything is still working
并确保一切正常。
as it should
理所应当
and then we relight the engines for about eight minutes
然后我们重新点燃引擎大约八分钟
this is called the earth escape burn
这就是所谓的地球逃生燃烧
this is what gets us on a path towards Mars
这让我们踏上了通往火星的道路
then the spacecraft separates
然后飞船分离
it's traveling at 41,000 kilometers per hour
它以每小时41000公里的速度飞行
and it will take about seven months to reach Mars
大约需要七个月才能到达火星。
our spacecraft is made up of a few pieces
我们的飞船由几块组成
here's the rover all folded up inside the descent stage
这是火星车在降落阶段折叠起来的样子
this has eight rocket engines on it
这上面有八个火箭引擎
the heat shield
隔热罩
which slows us down through the atmosphere
这会减慢我们在大气层中的速度
and protects the rover
并保护漫游者
the back shell
后壳
which protects the rover
保护漫游者
as it descends to the surface of
当它下降到表面时
Mars this is the cruise stage provides power
火星这是巡航级提供动力
fuel tanks and thrusters
油箱和推进器
and also keeps in communication with earth
并与地球保持联系
this whole assembly stays together
整个集会都在一起
during the seven month journey to Mars
在七个月的火星之旅中
we'll need to adjust our path along the way
一路上我们需要调整路线
we do this with the thrusters
我们用推进器来做这个
on the side of the cruise stage
在游轮舞台的一侧
this is called a trajectory correction maneuver or TCM
这叫做弹道修正机动或TCM
and there are several of them on the way to Mars
其中有几个正在去火星的路上。
landing on the surface of Mars
登陆火星表面
is nothing short of intense
简直就是激烈
they call this EDL or entry descent and landing
他们称之为EDL或入口下降和着陆
often nicknamed the 7 minutes of terror
常被戏称为恐怖的7分钟
this is because if anything goes wrong
这是因为如果出了什么差错
then we'll likely fail to get the rover
那我们可能就拿不到火星车了
safely to the surface
安全着陆
at the time of landing
着陆时
it will take about 11 minutes
大约需要11分钟
for any signals to reach earth
任何信号到达地球
this is of course traveling at the speed of light
这当然是以光速旅行
the fastest that we know how to communicate
我们知道如何最快地交流
it doesn't seem very fast does it
它看起来不是很快，是吗？
11 minutes is a long time
11分钟是很长的一段时间
to put this in perspective from earth to the moon
从地球到月球的角度来看
light takes just over 1 second to get there
光只需要1秒钟多一点就可以到达那里
when the Apollo astronauts were landing on the moon
当Apollo宇航员登陆月球时
NASA could communicate with them almost in real time
美国航天局几乎可以与他们实时通信
it would take about two and a/2 seconds
大约需要2.5秒。
to receive a reply
收到回复
on Mars this is completely
在火星上这完全是
if something goes wrong during the landing
如果着陆时出了什么问题
mission control won't hear about it for 11 minutes
任务控制中心11分钟内不会收到消息
and any reply would take another 11 minutes to get
任何回复都需要11分钟才能得到。
all the way back
一路回来
by this point it will already be over
到这时它已经结束了
either a safe landing or a crash
不是安全着陆就是坠机
this means the computers
这意味着电脑
electronics and the software
电子和软件
must be smart enough to do everything on their own
必须足够聪明，可以自己做任何事情
EDL entry descent and landing
EDL入口下降和着陆
let's follow this through step by step
让我们一步一步来
about 10 minutes before entering the atmosphere
大约在进入大气层前10分钟
the cruise stage
巡航阶段
is detached because it's no longer needed
是分离的，因为它不再需要了。
small thrusters on the backshell
后壳上的小型推进器
will now be used to steer the spacecraft
将被用来操纵飞船
next comes atmospheric entry
接下来是大气进入
the heat shield will protect the rover during this time
在这段时间里隔热罩会保护漫游者
once we get about 11 kilometers above the ground
一旦我们到达离地面11公里的地方
then the parachute can deploy
然后降落伞就可以展开了
it uses a technology called range trigger
它使用一种称为范围触发的技术
which finds out how close we are from the landing site
它会发现我们离着陆点有多近
and then deploys the parachute
然后打开降落伞
at just the right moment
在适当的时候
next step is heat shield separation
下一步是隔热罩分离
for the first time
第一次
the perseverance rover can now see the Martian surface
毅力漫游者现在可以看到火星表面了
down below
下面
now we use Terrain Relative Navigation
现在我们使用地形相对导航
the rover will be taking pictures of the ground beneath
漫游者将拍摄下面的地面
it and comparing these to maps of Mars
并将这些与火星地图进行比较
this will be used to safely steer the rover
这将用于安全驾驶漫游者
towards the intended landing site
朝着预定的着陆点
next comes backshell separation
接下来是后壳分离
all that's left is the descent stage and the rover
剩下的就是降落台和漫游者了
the rockets on the descent stage fire up
火箭在下降阶段发射
to slow us down
让我们慢下来
as we get closer to the surface
当我们接近地表
then the rover separates
然后漫游者分离
but still attached by some cables
但仍然由一些电缆连接
they call this the sky crane maneuver
他们称之为空中吊车机动
the final part everyone is waiting touchdown
最后一部分每个人都在等待触地得分
the cables are cut
电缆被切断了
and the descent stage
和下降阶段
flies off into the distance for a crash landing
飞向远方迫降
far away from the rover
远离漫游者
now it's time to check out the rover's systems
现在是时候检查漫游者的系统了
deploy the mast
展开桅杆
and then the robotic arm in the very front
然后是最前面的机械臂
the main purpose of the perseverance Rover
毅力罗孚的主要目的
is to look for signs of life
就是寻找生命的迹象
it landed in Jezreel Crater
它降落在Jezreel陨石坑
which
哪个
billions of years ago used to be filled with water
数十亿年前这里曾经充满了水
where there is water
有水的地方
there is usually life
通常有生命
or at least signs that life existed in the past
或者至少是过去存在生命的迹象
Perseverance Rover has an array of advanced
毅力漫游者有一系列先进的
scientific instruments to study the surface of Mars
研究火星表面的科学仪器
if you remember from earlier the rover is enormous
如果你还记得之前的火星车是巨大的
it's about the size of a car
大概有一辆车那么大
the main body of the rover they call the Web
漫游者的主体他们称之为网络
Warm Electronics Box
保暖电子盒
then you've got six wheels
那你就有六个轮子了
three on each side that are made of aluminum
两边各三个是铝制的
the front and back wheels can turn
前后轮都能转
allowing the rover to spin a full 360 degrees
让漫游者旋转整整360度
the suspension system
悬挂系统
allows the rover to travel over rough terrain
可以让漫游者在崎岖的地形上行驶
you never know what kind of obstacles
你永远不知道什么样的障碍
you're going to come across on Mars
你会在火星上遇到
but to be more realistic
但更现实一点
the rover would be going about this fast
漫游者会开得这么快
it has a top speed of 01 kilometers per hour
它的最高时速为01公里
the slow speed is mainly for the safety
速度慢主要是为了安全
and stability of the rover
和漫游者的稳定性
this is the remote sensing mast
这是遥感桅杆
this is the place where you'll find some of the cameras
这是你能找到一些摄像机的地方
and sensors of the rover
和漫游者的传感器
it's just a little taller than the height of a human
只是比人类的身高高一点
the idea is
想法是
to give us a similar view of what a person would see
让我们对一个人会看到什么有类似的看法
if they were here
如果他们在这里
on Mars
在火星上
this big circle up on top is called the Supercam
最上面的这个大圆圈叫作超级圆环。
it's basically a laser that can identify chemicals
它基本上是一种激光，可以识别化学物质
in rocks from as much as 7 meters away
在7米外的岩石中
this is the Mastcam Z
这是Mastcam Z
these are the main cameras on the rover
这些是探测器的主摄像头
that can even take high definition video
甚至可以拍摄高清视频
navigation
导航
cameras are used to help the rover safely drive
摄像头是用来帮助漫游者安全行驶的
on the surface of Mars
在火星表面
right below is the Mars Environmental Dynamics Analyzer
正下方是火星环境动力学分析仪
or meta
或元
this is studying the weather and atmosphere on Mars
这是在研究火星上的天气和大气层
the rover has two microphones one on the mast
漫游者有两个麦克风，一个在桅杆上
and then another on the side of the rover
然后另一个在漫游者的侧面
then we have the hascams
然后我们有hascams
which are short for hazard camera
这是危险摄像头的缩写
there's some in the front here
前面有一些
but also in the back
但也在后面
like the name says
就像名字说的
these cameras help avoid hazards and obstacles
这些摄像头有助于避免危险和障碍物
while driving around on Mars
在火星上开车时
the power source for the rover is called
漫游者的电源称为
the radioisotope
放射性同位素
thermoelectric generator
热电发电机
or RTG for short
或简称RTG
it's a nuclear power source
这是一个核动力源
the decay of radioactive elements generates heat
放射性元素的衰变产生热量
which can then be turned into electricity
然后可以转化为电能
some of the previous rovers used solar panels
以前的一些漫游者使用太阳能电池板
to generate power from the sunlight
利用阳光发电
but this doesn't work at night
但这在晚上不起作用
and if too much dust gets on it
如果上面有太多灰尘
well then it's game over
那么游戏结束了
both curiosity and perseverance used the RTG
好奇心和毅力都使用了RTG
which means a lot more flexibility in regards to power
这意味着在权力方面有更多的灵活性
this is
这是
rimpax or Radar Imager for Mars Subsurface Experiment
用于火星地下实验的rimpax或雷达成像仪
this uses radar waves to study the ground
这是利用雷达波来研究地面
up to 9 meters below the surface of Mars
在火星表面以下9米处
then there's Moxie
还有莫邪
Mars Oxygen in Situ Resource Utilization Experiment
火星氧原位资源利用实验
this takes the carbon dioxide on Mars
这把火星上的二氧化碳
and turns it into oxygen
并将其转化为氧气
this kind of technology will be very important
这种技术将非常重要
once we start sending humans to Mars
一旦我们开始把人类送上火星
and of course
当然还有
the robot arm in the very front of the rover
漫游者最前面的机械臂
this has a few tools
这有几个工具
at the end with some really big NASA acronyms
最后是美国航天局的缩写
so here we go Pixel
所以我们开始吧Pixel
this
这
helps to determine what chemicals make up the rocks
有助于确定构成岩石的化学物质
on a very small scale
在非常小的范围内
Watson another powerful camera
沃森另一个强大的相机
to see the rocks with fine detail
仔细观察岩石
and then Sherlock this provides fine scale imaging
然后夏洛克这个提供了精细的成像
at the end of the arm is the coring drill
臂的末端是取心钻
this is capable of drilling and collecting samples
这能够钻探和收集样本
that will be stored
那将被存储
on board the rover
在漫游者上
then it will take these samples and place them
然后它会采集这些样本并放置它们
inside of the rover
漫游者内部
future mission is planned
未来的任务已计划好
to take these samples from the surface of Mars
从火星表面采集这些样本
and return them to earth so we can study them further
并将它们送回地球以便我们进一步研究它们
so how does perseverance communicate back to earth
那么毅力是如何与地球沟通的呢？
the best way is to use the Mars Relay Network
最好的办法是使用火星中继网络
which consists of several satellites in
它由几颗卫星组成
orbit around Mars
环绕火星的轨道
these were launched long before
这些是很久以前推出的
perseverance got to Mars
毅力到达火星
these satellites are also used for science
这些卫星也用于科学研究
and to communicate with other rovers
并与其他漫游者交流
that are also on Mars
也在火星上
for example one of these
例如其中一个
satellites is called the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter
卫星叫做火星侦察轨道器
so perseverance can send data to the satellite
所以毅力可以向卫星发送数据
which will then send it directly back home to earth
然后将它直接送回地球
on the surface of Earth
在地球表面
NASA uses massive satellite dishes
美国航天局使用大量卫星天线
to communicate with spacecraft
与飞船通信
throughout the solar system
整个太阳系
this is part of the Deep Space Network
这是深空网络的一部分
there are three
有三个
main locations for these satellite dishes
这些卫星天线的主要位置
Boldstone California
加利福尼亚州博尔德斯通
Madrid Spain
马德里西班牙
in Canberra Australia
在澳大利亚堪培拉
no matter which way the earth is facing
无论地球面向哪个方向
it will always be able to receive signals from Mars
它将永远能够接收来自火星的信号
or other distant places in our solar system
或者太阳系其他遥远的地方
perseverance has three antennas on board
毅力号船上有三根天线
the UHF antenna or ultra high frequency antenna
UHF天线或超高频天线
this communicates directly with satellites above
这直接与上面的卫星通信
primarily used to send large amounts of information
主要用于发送大量信息
the high gain antenna
高增益天线
this transmits directly to and from earth
这直接传入和传出地球
and then the low gain antenna
然后是低增益天线
mostly used just to receive data from earth
主要用于接收来自地球的数据
of course we can't forget about ingenuity
我们当然不能忘记匠心
this is the helicopter that was sent to Mars
这是被送往火星的直升机
along with the rover
和漫游者一起
now where would you put a helicopter on the rover
现在你会把直升机放在漫游者的哪里？
look closely
仔细看
you'll see a little tiny black compartment right here
你会在这里看到一个小小的黑色隔间
this is where it was stored
这是存放它的地方
about two months after landing
着陆后大约两个月
the helicopter was finally deployed onto the surface
直升机最终被部署到地面上
the process took about a week to complete
这个过程花了大约一周的时间才完成
first the cover is removed and we expose the helicopter
首先把盖子拆了我们把直升机露出来
then it's unlatched carefully folded down
然后打开，小心地折叠起来。
the legs come out
腿出来了
and dropped onto the surface
并落到表面上
perseverance can drive away
毅力可以驱赶
and ingenuity can start to absorb the
独创性可以开始吸收
sunlight on its solar panels
太阳能电池板上的阳光
the helicopter has two rotors
直升机有两个旋翼
that rotate in opposite directions
以相反的方向旋转
on earth
在地球上
most helicopter blades spin at only a few hundred
大多数直升机叶片的转速只有几百
rpms or rotations per minute
每分钟转速
for a helicopter to work on Mars
让直升机在火星上工作
we have to spin the blades a lot faster
我们必须把刀片转得更快
this is because the air is much thinner here
这是因为这里的空气稀薄多了
the first test flight of ingenuity happened
第一次独创性的试飞发生了
about two months after landing on Mars
大约在登陆火星两个月后
the first helicopter to fly around on another planet
第一架在另一个星球上飞行的直升机
and it turned out to be a huge success
结果是一个巨大的成功
as of this video
从这个视频开始
there's been a handful of flights
有几个航班
and ingenuity is still operational
独创性仍在运作
perseverance paves the way for future missions
坚持不懈为未来的任务铺平道路
where we will
我们将在哪里
hopefully
满怀希望地
be able to return Martian samples back to earth
能够将火星样本送回地球
and of course the next major milestone
当然，下一个重要里程碑
sending humans to Mars
把人类送上火星